David Ian Mason

{Full-Stack Software Developer}

About me

I am a former pharmaceutical scientist turned software developer with a strong background in problem-solving, decision-making, teamwork, leadership and communication as well as a good understanding of the importance in documentation. I began this transition after completely falling for the constant learning and fast development of programming and as such I am looking forward to joining a team where I can use my dedication towards continuously improving myself, those around me and the code before me.

School of Code

Bootcamper | Sep 2023 - Present

- Chosen from thousands of applicants to complete an intense 16-week, full-stack development bootcamp.
- Developed full-stack JS apps using a number of tools such as React and PostgreSQL.
- Fast paced learning of new topics/aspects daily.
- Weekly hackathons putting newly taught concepts into practice.
- Pair and team programming daily during workshops, hackathons and projects.
- Active participation in the Design steps of apps through ideation, user research, creation of user personas as well as low & high fidelity wire-framing.
- Use of Agile methodology during teamwork focusing on early MVP development and iterative improvements.
- Helped other Bootcampers to understand new topics when they were struggling.

SoC Project - Memory Echo

Memory Echo is a spaced repetition app designed for School of Code bootcampers to record and study the many different topics learnt during the bootcamp. The app then applies spaced repetition practices to remind the bootcamper when to revise a topic.

This app was developed as a 1-week project using JS, HTML, CSS for the Front-end and JS, Rest APIs, Express.js and PostegreSQL for the Back-end. The team of 6 split into subgroups to develop different aspects of the MVP with a focus on learning by cycling teams through the different parts of the app to ensure all members understood and learnt from the apps coding. I started on the Back-end setting up the API using an MVC architecture design before moving to the Front-end to fix an issue regarding the responsive layout.

After completing the MVP, the app was presented to industry experts for their feedback and received high praise. The team has continued the development of Memory Echo in our own time.

Contact

- David_Mason_@hotmail.co.uk
- **Q** 07914 637 286
- linkedin.com/in/davidianmason1702
- ngithub.com/DayHikari
- **❷** Bedford, UK

Skills

Front-End:

| JavaScript | React | Next.js | | TypeScript | HTML | CSS |

Back-End:

| PostegreSQL | Rest API | | Express.js | Node.js |

Testing:

| Playwright | Vitest | Supertest | | Jest | React Testing Library |

Personal Projects

1 - Calculator

Solo project to practice conditional logic and DOM manipulation.

2 - WeatherApp

Solo project to practice the use of APIs, DOM manipulation through user interactions and conditional rendering.

3 - Rating Component

Pair project using Frontend Mentor to practice HTML and CSS as well as DOM manipulation.

<u>4 - 100 Day Code Blog</u>

Solo project to practice Database and MVC Rest API usage.

Experience

Achilles Therapeutics Ltd

Senior GMP Production Scientist | 2021 - 2023 GMP Production Scientist | 2020 - 2021

- Lead the team within the lab during manufacturing.
- Managed scheduling and personnel.
- Line managed two junior team members.
- Wrote documentation for processes and events.
- Completed projects to a high standard and tight deadlines.
- Work on and lead projects encompassing multiple departments.
- Communicated with stakeholders regarding projects.
- Helped with the continuous development of the manufacturing process.

Lonza

 Biotechnologist 2
 | 2019 - 2020

 Biotechnologist 1
 | 2018 - 2019

- Worked in varying teams daily.
- Communicated and worked with multiple departments.
- · Managed projects.
- Lead teams within the lab during manufacturing.
- Trained new members on the process.
- Problem-solving when an incident occurred.

Tesco

Cashier (Part-time) | 2017 - 2018

• Daily communication with many people from varying backgrounds.

Kinkowan Senior High School

Assistant Language Teacher | 2015 - 2017

- Thrived in a new culture while learning to speak the language.
- Worked in a pair alongside Japanese English teachers.
- Communicated both within and outside work with a variety of people from different backgrounds.

The Binding Site Company

Laboratory Technician | 2013 - 2014

• Worked as a team to ensure the quality of diagnostic products

Methodologies

| Agile | Waterfall | | TDD | Disney Ideation |

Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Communication
- Quick learner
- Problem-solving
- Organised
- Adaptability
- Leadership
- Decision-making
- Self driven
- Documentation

Personal

Outside of coding I really enjoy gaming, in particular grand-strategy and city-building games as they require me to actively plan for different scenarios and react to constantly changing situations. I also enjoy reading and listening to books. I have recently started 'The Wheel of Time' by Robert Jordan which I am thoroughly enjoying. I have also been teaching myself how to play the violin which has been a very difficult experience as I am not musically inclined however I can hear myself progressing (slowly) and am looking forward to playing well!

Education

BSc (Hons) Biochemistry

Sheffield Hallam University | 2011 - 2015 1st-Class Degree